And here we are back in the Jupyter Lab for the fast approaching conclusion with a really great project.
다시 주피터 연구실입니다 곧 결과가 나올 텐데 아주 멋진 프로젝트가 있어요
Super satisfying.
정말 만족스러워요
Wait till you see.
기대해도 좋아요
So this time we're going to start by looking at two more of our simple agents.
이번에는 두 가지의 단순한 에이전트를 더 살펴볼게요
Probably the simplest we've got.
가장 간단한 방법일 거예요
There's one called the Messaging Agent, which we will use to be sending messages, and one called the
메시지를 보내는 데 쓰는 메시지 에이전트도 있고 활동을 조율하는
planning agent, which will coordinate activities.
기획 에이전트도 있어요
And both of these agents are ones which are just Python code.
이 에이전트들은 파이썬 코드로 되어있죠
They're not using Llms, and there's no reason why they can't be beefed up to use Llms.
그들은 LM을 사용하지 않아요 LM을 사용하도록 강화하지 않을 이유가 없죠
The messaging agent sends a notification, but of course, it could first make a quick call to a frontier
에이전트는 통지를 보내지만 먼저 개척자 모델에
model to improve that, to make it something that's juicier and that that is, is relevant to that particular
빠르게 연락해 더 맛있고 해당 제품과 관련 있는 제품을 개선할 수
deal.
있죠
So there's plenty that can be done here.
할 수 있는 게 많아요
And the planning agent, it's written in code.
기획 담당자는 코드로 돼 있고요
You could experiment with turning that into an LLM.
LLM으로 바꾸는 실험을 할 수 있어요
Getting to plan out what happens itself.
무슨 일이 일어날지 계획하는 거죠
But we'll at least see them and use them both in a second.
하지만 잠시 후에 둘 다 보게 될 거예요
Uh, and um, we're going to then afterwards put all of that into our agent framework.
그 후에 모든 걸 에이전트 프레임워크에 넣을 거예요.
But you can imagine, because we've put all of the building blocks together, the final part of having
하지만 모든 구성 요소를 합쳤기 때문에 에이전트 프레임워크
an agent framework is a cinch.
만드는 건 식은 죽 먹기죠
It's going to be just very straightforward.
아주 간단할 거예요
So let's start by talking about the messaging agent.
메신저 에이전트 얘기부터 하죠
This is the agent that's able to send us alerts when it finds a great deal.
좋은 물건을 찾으면 경보를 보내주는 중개인이죠
Um, and originally my plan was to send text messages for this.
원래는 문자 메시지를 보내려고 했어요
And I was going to use Twilio, which is a lovely framework that I've used in the past, but there's
트윌리오를 쓰려고 했어요 예전에 쓰던 프레임워크가 정말 좋았는데 최근에 규제가 많아져서
been a lot of regulations recently that makes it really quite hard to set up a Twilio account to send
트윌리오 계정으로 문자 보내기가 정말 어려워요 심지어 자기 자신한테도요
text messages, even to yourself, even when you've validated your own phone number and you want to
자기 전화번호를 확인해서 자기한테 문자 보내고 싶어도 서류 작업을
send yourself text messages, you have to fill in a fair bit of paperwork.
많이 해야 해요
If you're in the US now, that might be a lot easier in other countries.
미국에 산다면 다른 나라에서는 훨씬 수월할 거예요
It does seem to suggest on the website that that it's just a US restriction that makes it so hard.
웹사이트에 따르면 미국 내 제한 때문에 규제가 어려워진 것 같아요
And Twilio has a free plan.
트윌리오가 공짜 요금제를 줬어요
Twilio is also free to make WhatsApp messages as well.
트윌리오가 왓츠앱 메시지를 보내도 되고요
So you can have it.
그러니 가져요
WhatsApp and I did have it working whatsapping myself, but there are some constraints that you just,
왓츠앱과 저도 왓츠앱으로 작동시켰지만 제약이 좀 있었어요 샌드박스를
um, you can only use the free thing if you're using a sandbox which has some limitations, and you
써야만 무료로 사용할 수 있는데 거기엔 제한이 있어요 하루 중 특정 시간 사이에만
can only do it between certain hours of the day.
사용할 수 있죠
So it wasn't ideal.
이상적인 상황은 아니었죠
So it was okay.
그래서 괜찮았어요
And I've kept the code here so you can use it if you wish.
코드를 여기 뒀으니 원하면 사용하세요
But then I discovered something really, as I say, nifty called pushover.
그러다 정말 멋진 걸 발견했죠 만만한 거요
Uh, there's a few things like pushover, but pushover was was the one that I found to be the nicest
호구도 몇 가지 있지만 호구가 먹어본 것 중에 가장
of the ones I tried.
좋았어요
Um.
네
And pushover is a simple website where you can go and you set up an account.
푸시오버는 간단한 웹사이트로 계정을 설정할 수 있어요
It's free.
공짜예요
Uh, and you then download an app.
앱을 다운로드 하세요
In fact, you don't need to go to the website.
사실 웹사이트에 갈 필요도 없어요
You can.
할 수 있어요
The website is pushover dot net, not.com.
그 웹사이트는 푸시오버닷넷이에요 코무요
Uh, they weren't obviously weren't able to afford.com.
비용을 감당할 수 없었던 거죠 코무요
It's still up for grabs.
아직 몰라요
But pushover dot net is their website.
푸시오버닷넷이 그 웹사이트예요
And then there's an app called pushover.
푸시오버라는 앱도 있어요
Uh And it's free to set up.
설치도 자유롭게 할 수 있어요
At least it's free for up to 10,000 messages.
적어도 10,000번까진 무료예요
And I think we're not likely for this particular project to get close to that.
이 프로젝트는 그런 목표에 도달하지 못할 것 같아요. Get up! Get up!
You can see I've managed to get to 35 messages of my allowance so far.
지금까지 용돈 메시지를 35개나 보냈어요. Get up! Get up!
Um, and now the reason this page looks a bit janky is that I've scrolled down because it shows above
이 페이지가 좀 조잡해 보이는 이유는 스크롤을 내렸기 때문이에요 이 위에 제
here my tokens in big letters, and I didn't particularly want to reveal all of my tokens to all of
토큰이 큰 글자로 표시돼 있거든요 제 토큰을 전부 보여드리고 싶진 않았어요
you.
아니면 온종일 통보할 수도 있고요
So yeah, it's hard not to miss the tokens as soon as you sign up for your free pushover account.
그러니 토큰을 놓치지 않을 수가 없죠 무료 푸시버 계정에 가입하는 순간요
I promise I'm not affiliated, but it's, uh, seems to be really, really helpful.
전 관련 없다고 약속하지만 정말 도움이 많이 돼요
Um, once you've signed up, you then take your tokens and you can then easily send push notifications
일단 등록을 하면 토큰을 가지고 쉽게 푸시 알림을 보낼 수 있습니다 그러면 토큰 두 개가
so you'll end up with two tokens a pushover user, which is a token that applies to, uh, to you.
남게 되는데 푸시오버 사용자는 여러분에게 적용되는 토큰이죠
And then you have to set up each of your applications, and you just choose one.
그런 다음 각각의 응용 프로그램을 셋업하고 하나만 선택하세요
And I called it preserve for me and you can give it a token.
전 그걸 보존이라고 불렀고 토큰을 줄 수 있어요
Um, and sorry, you can't.
미안하지만 안 돼요
You get given a token once you've set up your application for that.
Get in 응용 프로그램을 설정하면 토큰을 받아요
Uh, and these two things you should add to the EMV file.
EMV 파일에 추가해야 할 두 가지가 있어요
Wonderfully.
아주 잘 지내요
You can also upload a, um, an image, uh, associated with your application.
응용 프로그램과 관련된 이미지를 업로드 할 수도 있어요
And I found an image, uh, looking around of a stack of coins.
동전 더미를 둘러보다가 스택을 발견했어요
And so I uploaded that because it's great.
그래서 그걸 업로드했어요 멋지잖아요
When I get a push notification, there's a little image comes up and it comes up on my Apple Watch as
푸시 알림을 받으면 작은 이미지가 뜨는데 제 애플 워치에도 뜨죠.
well.
스택 스크린 전체가 동전 더미로 바뀌는데 정말 재미있어요
So you might want to do the same thing.
여러분도 같은 걸 하고 싶을 거예요
Find a find a cute image to go with.
어울리는 귀여운 이미지를 찾으세요
Push over if you use that.
그걸 쓰면 옆으로 밀어요
Um, as I say, if you if you are able to, if you either already have a Twilio account or if you go
말씀드렸듯이 가능하다면 이미 트윌리오 계정이 있거나 방문해
there and you see that it is straightforward in whatever country you're joining from, then by all means
보면 가입한 나라가 어디든 아주 간단해요 어떻게든 문자를
you can do that instead and get a text, a bona fide, uh, SMS text message instead of a push notification.
받을 수 있죠 푸시 알림 대신 SMS 문자 메시지를요
But push notifications are all we need for this.
하지만 푸시 알림만 있으면 돼요
Okay.
네
So I'm going to go straight to this this class messaging agent under agents.
바로 이 클래스 메시지 에이전트로 갈게요 에이전트 하의 에이전트요
Messaging agent is one of our agents.
메시지를 보내는 요원도 우리 요원이에요
Here it is.
여기 있네요
It's very straightforward.
아주 간단해요
It is basically a wrapper around the Twilio API and around the pushover API.
기본적으로 트윌리오 API와 무허가 API를 감싸는 래퍼예요
And I've got at the top do text and do push as two constants that you can set, because if you wish,
상단에 텍스트 do와 push를 설정할 수 있는 두 상수로 설정했어요 원하시면 어느
I didn't want to make it a either or because you can have both, you can have it text you and push notify
쪽도 아닌 둘 다 가질 수 있으니까요 텍스트 do와 push를
you if that is what you desire.
원하는 경우에 설정할 수 있죠
So there's an init, uh, constructor which sets up, um, the, the various, uh, criteria.
이닛, 즉 생성자가 다양한 기준을 설정해요
If you're doing push notification, like me, as I say, you need pushover user and pushover token,
푸시 알림을 하고 있다면 저처럼요 푸시오버 사용자와 푸시오버 토큰이 필요하다면
and you can always just type it straight in here if you don't want to faff around with env files, um,
여기에 바로 입력하면 됩니다 imf 파일로 번거롭게 하고 싶지 않다면요
obviously, then don't push this code.
그럼 이 코드를 푸시하지 마세요
Uh, and if you're using Twilio, then you need to have an account Sid and auth token.
트윌리오를 사용하려면 계정 시드, 인증 토큰이 필요해요
A Twilio from, which is the number that Twilio will give you, is the number that it's coming from.
트윌리오가 알려줄 번호가 발신 번호예요
And then the phone number that you want it to text message to.
그리고 문자 메시지를 보낼 전화번호도 있어요
And so I have these four in my env file.
제 부럽게도 이 4개가 있죠
But I'm not using it because I filled in the paperwork just to have done it.
하지만 안 쓸 거예요 서류는 작성했으니까요
But I haven't yet been granted authorization to send a text message to myself.
하지만 아직 나한테 문자 보내도 된다는 인가는 못 받았어요
Uh, but hopefully that's going to come one of these days.
조만간 그렇게 되길 바라야죠
In the meantime, the push notifications are great.
그동안 푸시 알림은 훌륭하죠
So I've then got two, uh, methods here message, which is simply a wrapper around the Twilio API,
메서드가 2개 있는데 메시지는 Twilio API를 감싸는 래퍼예요
which as you can see, it's really simple.
보다시피 아주 간단하죠
It's it's the Twilio client dot messages dot create.
Twilio 클라이언트 .Message.Create예요
And you say who it's coming from and the text and who it's going to, and that's it.
누가 보낸 문자인지 누구에게 보낼 건지 말하면 끝이죠
And it will send a text message.
문자 메시지도 보내죠
I've used it before.
전에 써봤어요
It just works.
그냥 잘 맞아요
Receiving text messages is pretty easy too.
문자 받는 것도 꽤 쉬워요
You just have to have an endpoint that gets called a webhook.
웹훅이라 불리는 엔드포인트가 있어야 해요
Um, and but obviously we don't need to do that.
하지만 그럴 필요는 없어요
Uh, the push notification is also very simple.
푸시 알림도 아주 간단해요
Um, we but it doesn't have it doesn't use an API because they, they, they're sort of keen to point
API 사용은 안 해요 웹사이트에서 의도적이라는 걸 꼭 지적하고
out, I think, on their website that it's intentional.
싶어 하거든요
They just want to keep it as straightforward as possible.
최대한 단순하게 가고 싶어 해요
They don't even use the requests library in their example code because they wanted to say, you don't
예제 코드에서 요청 라이브러리도 사용하지 않아요 아무것도 불러올 필요가 없다고
need to import anything.
말하고 싶으니까요
You can just simply use out of the box Python to send a push notification.
단순히 out out a box 파이썬을 이용해서 푸시 알림을 보낼 수 있어요.
Uh, and you simply pass in the token, uh, the message.
토큰으로 메시지를 전달하면 돼요
And optionally you can include a sound.
선택적으로 소리를 포함할 수도 있어요
And I one of the ones that they suggest as being available is called cash Register.
그리고 제가 제안한 것 중 하나가 현금 등록기라는 건데요
And it makes a very pleasing cash register sound when I get the notification, which is great fun.
알림을 받으면 아주 기분 좋은 계산대 소리가 나요 Get it! 아주 재미있죠
Uh, and that's all there is to it.
그게 전부인 것 같아요
And then there's an alert, uh, method here, which, based on whether you're texting or pushing it,
그리고 알림 메서드가 있어요 문자를 보내든 푸시를 하든 뭔가
will construct something to tell you about.
설명할 걸 생성하죠
And it will then send a message and it takes an opportunity.
그리고 메시지를 보내는데 기회를 잡는 거죠
So you pass in an opportunity and you'll get a message about that opportunity.
Get in get 기회를 놓치면 그 기회에 대한 메시지를 받게 되죠
You remember, opportunity is the object that we looked at down here that has a deal, an estimate and
기억하시죠? 기회는 우리가 여기서 본 객체입니다 할인과 견적서, 할인을 가지고
a discount.
있죠
All right.
좋아요
But first let's just quickly try it out.
하지만 먼저 빨리 시험해 보죠
I should just be able to create an instance of this.
이것의 인스턴스를 생성할 수 있어야 해요
And I should be able to say massive news and ping my phone just went.
엄청난 소식을 전하면 핑이 울려야 하는데 말이죠
Now, unfortunately, I have quite aggressive noise filter on my microphone to to only bring out voice.
안타깝게도 마이크에 있는 노이즈 필터가 너무 공격적이라 목소리만 나오게 돼 있어요
So I imagine you didn't hear the cash register as I say, very pleasing indeed.
금전 등록기 소리를 못 들으셨나 봐요 정말 기분 좋네요
Luckily you'll be able to hear it for yourself when you try it out.
직접 해 보시면 들을 수 있을 거예요
Uh, and yeah, I'm going to have to hear that again just because I love it.
네, 그 말 다시 듣고 싶어요 너무 좋거든요
Uh, there it goes.
저기 가네요
And yeah, my watch two has has come up.
네, 시계 2호도 있어요
So it's, um.
그래서... 네
Yeah, very satisfactory indeed.
네, 아주 만족스러워요
That then is the, uh, the messaging agent.
그 메시지 전달원이란 사람이에요
I will see you next time for the planning agent.
기획사 일로 다음에 뵙죠